yeah you're absolutely right you just
named off everything that's going to go
on at the conference um before i comment
on that he's had his hand up for that
yeah
[Music]
deals with uh
[Applause]
[Music]
field's coming off of this
our workshop speaker this afternoon
is vernon roth want to welcome you all
to the 2011
extraordinary technology conference and
vernon
it's always a challenge to introduce him
because one of the things that happens
in this field is sometimes professional
relationships turn into friendships
and in a way that's one of the most
wonderful parts of being in this field
because so many people are open to
friendship
vernon has worked a lot with ancient
tech
a company that makes and provides
different ointments and salves and
things like that and he is literally
responsible for
how healthy i feel right now because one
of his
products has actually been working very
well for my own personal situation
vernon said in way of introduction the
best thing to say is that his work
stands for itself i really believe that
it's just incredible work and let's
welcome vernon
roth thank you
all right here we go
um
when i was approached about speaking
here at the conference i had
some i had a very set idea and set
agenda on what i was going to be
speaking on presenting
and in the course of this summer
some really amazing things happened and
i've had to re-examine my paradigm of
the universe and so i'm going to
presenting be presenting some of that
today
perspectives can change
ideas can change but um
what we are we are on the cutting edge
the the absolute forefront of the
experimental of the experimental
community and to finish the to finish
the uh the analogy um when uh that we
were talking about a little bit earlier
when
the university gets something he uh he
mentioned that it's 20 years old this
experiment these experiments saying that
light produced magnetism is now being
done in the university and they're
saying oh wow we found a new source of
energy because light can create
magnetism in these rods and it
oscillates and changes and all we have
to do is let the sunlight flow through
the rods and we'll have power
this is 20 year old technology and i
know the guys that did in their basement
20 years ago
okay
so
what we have to do and i'll talk a
little bit more about
the mental paradigm that we have to
adopt as as we go through this con as we
go through this uh presentation
um what we have to do is we have to
adopt the paradigm that says
i can
not somebody else can we can't wait for
it to be available in walmart we gotta
we've gotta you know create it in our
own in our own sphere um
one of the uh well let's let us let us
move forward oh look i have a i have a
button here and i can move forward
okay
um
my work is all with water and and uh
i found that i found that water is one
of the most important things that we can
ever ever study
uh this this year i had my i had some
really amazing uh
discoveries and i saw some really
amazing things i saw water levitate this
year
uh there are some people in the in the
audience that saw this with me i saw
well i saw a column of three ounces of
water literally levitating off of a
grain of sand
because someone understood the essential
nature of water
okay
let me tell you something i'm gonna i'm
gonna throw some numbers out here but i
want to i want to i want to blow a
paradigm here real quick
since this is a workshop and we don't
have a super
we don't have a firm definite time limit
try this experiment sometime
okay
go out and gather rain water okay
go out and gather rain water and get
about a gallon or two gallons of the
rain water put it into a put it into a
glass jar a large glass jar
and let it sit
and ferment maybe or or just sit in age
set it out in the sun set it out
someplace covered so it can't uh
evaporate let it sit and age
you're going to let it sit in age for
about two or three months give or take
then you take that gallon of water
remember you've got a gallon of water
and so we're going to we're going to
distill it and we're not going to use
the stainless steel distiller that you
buy at walmart for 75 dollars all those
are those are a good deal don't get the
aluminum ones get the stainless steel
we're going to distill it in like an
alcohol distiller maybe glass maybe
stainless steel but really nice one
you distill off one quart of water okay
and we're going to set that cord of
water and we're going to set it over
here and we're going to call that
fire
all right
we're going to distill off another quart
of water
we're going to set that right here
we're going to call that one air
it's still off a third cord of water and
we're going to call that earth
and then we're we we have to distill the
last one we're going to distill the last
one and we'll have
one last court and that's uh we're going
to call that water so we've now we've
created what they call a fractal okay
we've got earth air
excuse me uh fire air earth and water
now
take those courts
and
freeze them
all right or try and freeze them
because what you will actually find
what i found this this uh this winter
was that the first court of water that i
distilled off that i labeled fire
wouldn't freeze and at minus 10 degrees
all right
would not freeze at all
got a little goldish hue to it
i thought that was really interesting
goldish hue doesn't freeze
now i've experienced non-freezing water
before the electric water
will oftentimes not freeze until you
shake it and move it yes
what's that
uh minus 10 f fahrenheit i usually don't
play with celsius um
the second quarter of water oh heck that
freezes that freezes 30 somewhere around
32 to you know 30 degrees but what's
interesting is
when that froze
all sorts of little air bubbles
formed in the freezing water and it
expanded up just incredibly uh excuse me
a large magnitude of size
as if it was expanding for all of the
other water that you'd separated out
okay
and interestingly we labeled that air
right
so literally that is the fractal of air
from water
the third cord of water which we labeled
earth that's frozen that freezes
somewhere around 32 to
30 degrees as well
but it hasn't expanded at all and it's
completely clear
and the last court of water that we have
labeled um water
well heck that doesn't freeze and i've
heard uh stories of people taking it
down to minus 100
okay
so what i've just done
is i've kind of blown the paradigm
of water freezing at 32 degrees
i've completely changed all and all this
you can try this this is an old
alchemical trick because every single
part of that water every single fractal
that we just separated
has a distinct purpose okay and if you
want to play with hydrogen
you take
you take the fire
and the air fractals that you did and
put that in your hydrogen
and have fun with it okay
because this is this is a this is a
paradigm shift okay uh when i learned
this i said wait a minute this can't be
possible and i tried it and i did it and
that's just like a little bit of what
happened we'll talk about more because
like i said my mind was blown so many
times this year it's been amazing i mean
you start to think that you actually
know something you start to think that
you're actually on the right track and
then you discover wait a minute
everything that i taught maybe was wrong
i was just at a uh who was at the the
anoda conference out uh back in georgia
oh there you guys are okay
um it was really amazing because uh
i said a few things that i was at a uh
international alchemy conference and
there was there was about uh about 75
alchemists ormus specialists from around
the world and i said a few things that
kind of blew their paradigm and they
came up to me afterwards and said wait a
minute that can't be right and i said
who
who told you that uh
that that can't be right and said well
science says that that can't be right
and i said the same scientists that say
that 99 of what we do is impossible
so
think about that as as we're going
through this today okay i also want to
throw out some numbers here
i want to throw out some paradigm
shifting numbers how many people are
there in the world today
6.6 billion uh we're getting close to 7
billion
40 years how many people are going to be
there
if
if uh populations continue to expand the
way they are going
we'll be looking about 9 billion in 40
years okay
here's a number for you
in the next 40 years
we have to produce more food
in this on this planet than we have in
the last 8 000
okay
now
when you look at the numbers we waste
about half of the food that has grown on
this planet this has nothing to do with
greed it has nothing to do with um we're
going to keep this population under our
thumb it has nothing to do with any of
that it's simply a flawed system of
producing food but we waste about half
of our food
but even if we had all of that food we
still have to find a completely new
paradigm of growing food in the next 40
years otherwise we're going to be in
trouble and then we'll be back to the 5
billion as he said
all right
so these are some numbers and i'll throw
out some more of these numbers that you
need to be thinking about as we go into
this conference it's not just this
lecture
it's this this entire conference
should be a paradigm shift something
that teaches us something new a new way
of thinking a new way of acting a new
way of resonating with our world so
we're going to be talking about hydrogen
these gentlemen are very interested in
hydrogen and you're all here this is a
significant portion of the hydrogen
lecture um
safety the art of triple redundancy
anybody's star trek fans
okay and they're always about
multiple layers of redundancy somehow
they always seem to fail but we won't go
into that um
i love safety i had some explosions in
my shop this year
oh boy howdy they were interesting
because when you play with hydrogen
oxygen it is the most explosive force in
the universe
and you have to be careful with that so
i really love safety
what you see on the uh
let's see here
[Music]
look at that okay what you see on the
left hand side is there a way to dim the
lights on the screen guys
is that possible
what you see on the left hand side is my
safety setup
down here
is my hydrogen is my hydrogen device it
looks a lot like this
i'll show you another one in that box it
looks very similar
the the gas comes out of the hydrogen
device goes up here to a little
reservoir thank you very much
goes up to a little
reservoir and cycles so the hydrogen
device pushes hydrogen and water up into
there the the water returns down there
and there's a little cooling uh
heatsink right there you don't i don't
actually need it but i just put it there
for kicks and giggles
hydrogen forms in here goes up through
this tube and into this column of water
a column of water working with hydrogen
is very important
because
if you have a column of water you
actually remember we're getting come
back to water here you actually magnify
the power of the hydrogen okay so if you
just have it going through an inch or
two of water you know that's good for
safety
but
the the taller the water you magnify the
hydrogen now here's a here's one to play
with
put a rodent coil around that
and then
shine ultraviolet light through that
okay you multiply the power of your
hydrogen you multiply the power of your
browns gas
those are some secrets that uh
that took me a long time to figure out
and learn about um
actually what's interesting about using
ultraviolet light is very similar to uh
um anybody familiar with uh with
laser refinement of uranium this is not
secret this is not a top secret thing
uranium is refined by
literally
a vacuum distillation of the uranium ore
running it through a column like this
and hitting it with lasers
that are resonating at the frequency of
the desired uranium so we take uranium
what is it 92 no i don't remember
it's fairly low and we can write make
uranium 235 or 238 or whatever
using simply vacuum distillation
resonating it with lasers and boom we
drop out and we have
we have vapor deposit and we create uh
uranium or we create uh
refined uranium same thing with
plutonium it's a it's a common process
but what we're seeing here is hey we're
going to change the nature of an element
using just frequency input
there's a paradigm thought right there
okay so the gas flows up through this
through this column of water and it's
actually only filled about that high
but uh
i'll tell you what 10 liters a minute
will force bubbles all the way up to the
top of there if you ever see if somebody
says well i've got a i've got a unit
that creates 10 liters a minute and if
you're not seeing bubbles that are
half the size of your fist coming out of
there like crazy they're lying
or they're they're they're thinking that
they have an ideal scenario but it's i
guess that's a more polite way of
putting it
10 liters a minute will force that water
up that tube and and bubbles will come
all the way up this high
okay so that's my first stage and i have
a safety valve that i can
cut that off and let it let it evaporate
out and or let it boil off into the air
if something happens over here
next the water travels through this
black tube and into this stainless steel
bubbler anybody familiar with george
wiseman's
work anybody seen a george wiseman
browns gas generator
okay he has a stainless steel thing
that's uh
about a foot and a half tall 12 inches
on the base and it's a very heavy duty
device and that's his a flashback
arrestor that's what you're seeing right
there that's a safety
that will absorb the blast of a hydrogen
of a hydrogen flashback and you don't
you don't want the hydrogen flashback
that is my that is my last line of
safety actually this is my last line of
safety but this is my
um
last line of real safety
and that keeps any any hydrogen blast
from coming back out and i've got a
little sight gauge on the on the side so
i can see how much water is in there and
all that
the gas then flows out of the top of
that up into this uh to another
um
safety device
and that is this one someone will come
up and i'll pass this around
one up here and i'll uh
somebody
there you go yeah take that pass it
around
that is
a flashback arrester okay
who here has bought flashback arrestors
okay
um really good flashback arrester you
get it for uh you get a two pack for 40
bucks at at um
us air air gas supply that type of stuff
um i've tried it it works with hydrogen
it works with brown's gas so
it's very important don't go out and buy
a plastic thing you can make a plastic
thing really easily for this stage but
over here you want
a metal flashback arrestor okay
like i said i've had explosions i made
explosions on purpose to see where
things can fail
okay now if that's not insane i don't
know what it is but
i did it on purpose to see where things
can fail so that's your that's your
first line of defense
unless if you don't turn off a torch
fast enough you can get a flashback okay
now how how weird is that that's it
that's that's really fun to play with
um
you can make your own flashback arrester
using one like this
and i'll pass this around
there you go
these cost about 40 bucks at
surplus stores and such
really good little stainless steel deals
they are so dynamic you can use them for
a lot of things yes
i don't use brass wool or stainless i
uh they have something inside of that
flashback arrester but i don't use that
i use water
water in this water in this vessel
and then whatever mechanism they use
inside of that little flashback arrestor
passing around
because i it's it's just it's just
easier to state of mind it is an
industry standard they use it for
hydrogen they use it for explosive gases
so i just said all right i've played
around i've blown some stuff up i want
to use this here and and like i said
it's 40 bucks for a pair so you know
it's it's it's a it's a nice way to stay
safe
um
you don't actually need this in a car by
the way but we'll get to that all right
and this is an up close of the of the
the bubbler device
um the art of triple redundancy um
you know what that didn't make it into
the car
uh
pressure switches there are pressure
switches you can get for 16 bucks from
allied
allied switch
if you turn off your device
it automatically shuts or if you close
your whole your torch that automatically
shuts off when you get to uh
two or three psi very important to play
with that so
that's something to think about
okay
um
these are this is my preparatory deal i
want everybody to be aware of the safety
involved like i've said i've had
explosions happen i've made explo
explosions and
you want to you want to avoid that as
much as possible i've been very blessed
my angels have have blessed me i had one
thing explode in my early alchemical
days
just i always set it there and just you
know let it go and
one day
something inside my said head said no
you want to you want to you want to make
that look good sitting there like why
it's it's just pressure now you want to
make that look good so i propped it up
and put it every put it everywhere and
or put some things around it to keep it
from falling over and then i started my
experiments over here and
this thing had exploded it sent a uh it
sent basically what you're the big thing
that you're passing around it sent the
top of that through the ceiling through
a couple of joists and embedded in the
asphalt shingles on the outside of my
house
okay the three ball bearings inside of
it
missed my head like that
just
and embedded themselves like bullets in
the wall behind me
and the base that it was sitting on was
sitting on a a a a steel table top that
was uh half an inch thick and it put a
nice little concave
indentation in there about about a half
an inch thick inside that thing so
that was not hydrogen but i'm telling
you
i learned you know when you when when
death you know knocks at your door like
that you you you learn a few things so
safety is key
all right
we're going to move on
because i i wanted to i wanted to stress
this and the reason why i wanted to
stress this is because
i saw a lot of people and i'll talk
about this later a little bit more is
that i saw a lot of people playing with
hydrogen on the internet and it was
actually kind of scary because you got
guys
cooking things and then feeding it into
fans blowing it into your house you're
breathing
stainless or you're breathing fumes from
burning metal and stuff like that
you know i like i like people i like
people to come back to the conference
and i don't want anybody to die so
please think about that
okay we're going to talk about some of
the uh
some of the ways that we can generate
hydrogen my background with hydrogen is
that i've been working with internal
combustion engines and so we take the we
take the power
we take the power off of the alternator
we put it into the hydrogen device and
then we feed it feed the hydrogen back
into the internal combustion engine and
this is uh this works i mean we were i
mean 84 percent on on a honda accord 112
percent on gmc yukons 30 on semi trucks
40 percent on the uh the engines running
oil wells and such
but there's a problem in this world and
they're the problem is a paradigm and
it's very getting very difficult to uh
getting very difficult actually putting
these things on semi trucks is now very
much illegal okay just barely found out
about this a friend of mine
runs a shipping company and through a
fluke
one of his trucks
was uh
running empty almost empty loads for
about a month and so his gas mileage
went from four to seven okay which is
about the increase that we were seeing
with with hydrogen four miles to the
gallon to seven miles per gallon with
full loads
um
but
when all the numbers went through the
system they had an inspector there
within the next week wanting to find out
what they'd put on that semi truck to
change the gas mileage because they were
going to cut it off
okay they're cutting off hydrogen
devices they're cutting off magnets
they're cutting off things that you know
the little the little devices that are
going in there um
and they're being quiet about it but
it's happening so if you're working in
that field be careful
um
so what i'm talking about today
one of my paradigms is the idea of a of
how do we as a people
survive any
cataclysmic or
paradigm shifting changes in our world
okay so that's one of the things that
i'm talking want to talk about today
um and so i started looking at different
ways to generate hydrogen
and of course
there's the conventional we
hook up a solar panel or assuming a hook
up a windmill generator
to an alternator
and run it directly into your hydrogen
device and this device right here which
i have to say and i'll talk about it in
a little while this is probably one of
the most important
devices i have ever made and ever talked
about okay it doesn't look like much it
looks like a couple of pieces of of pvc
plastic and a stainless steel top but
we'll get to that but
this device is my first device that i've
ever made that runs specifically off
solar and what you see here
this little this little solar panel it's
a it's a tool charger from harbor
freight ah thank you it's a tool charger
from harbor freight
and it doesn't generate a whole lot of
power
but that device plus this device creates
20 liters an hour of gas
okay
now that's not a whole lot when you're
trying to boost a car
or boost it you know we put these things
on big giant uh
tugboat engines really amazing results
with that so 20 liters an hour is not
not much to talk about but if you store
20 liters an hour
and you do that for six hours a day
suddenly
you have enough
fuel
to cook all your food
and you don't have to buy propane you
don't have to you know you don't have to
be part of the system suddenly you have
taken a step
towards independence so
i i built this to illustrate that point
but then it became so much more um solar
of course uh
the device that up here is there
oh wait um i'll show you in a little bit
a friend of mine has a uh
has a
uh
a big place in the mountains he runs
shipping and he's a pretty interesting
little fellow
he ordered a hydrogen device that he
wants to plug into his diesel generator
and what we actually figured out was
that this device that i will show you
plus maybe one more hooked up to his
he's got a 2000 watt array of of solar
panels
hooked up to a 2000 watt array of solar
will boost his
diesel engine
90 percent because there's no parasitic
load he's not pulling off of the engine
and putting back into it he's got um
he's got 2000 watts of solar panel
boosts his uh diesel engine and he can
actually run his entire facility
off of a diesel generator plus this okay
so we'll talk about that a little bit
more but that's um that's one of the
things that that
that you can do with this hydro of
course there's really no difference
between any of these wind generates
most windmill generators generate uh
dc electricity that you can plug into a
hydrogen device that is tuned for it
um and we can talk about the tuning here
pretty soon um
solar same deal oh i went back to uh i
went to college this year and took some
uh alternative energy courses which were
very interesting i learned about three
days worth of stuff in the entire
semester which is really sad
but one of the interesting things is
that it's so easy now to go off grid
okay it is so easy
it requires money but but that's another
story entirely and we'll talk about more
about that later but so somebody remind
me about that um
but you can go off grid in so many
different ways and actually send money
back and here's a little trick there are
incentives in your taxes to
refit with solar or wind or some type of
alternative power
anybody know the percentages
they know the percentage of refund yes
okay so he gets
so he can get up about 40 percent refund
on a solar system so if you put in a 10
000 system you've only spent you only
spend actually six thousand dollars but
here's how to get it for free
yeah
i'm sorry i couldn't quite hear that
yes it is the cost of materials so
you're going to have to do the work
yourself to put it in place is what he
said not the labor just the cost of
materials but here's how you get it for
free there is another tax form
that allows you to depreciate
all the technology that you put into
your house
and you can do it all in one year and
literally you can get it for free and a
friend of mine did this
he put in a 60 thousand dollar solar
system got the tax rebates and then did
the tax form depreciated it all in one
year and he got the actually depreciated
in two years because he didn't need it
all in one year
got the whole thing for free
all taken care of yes
thank you that's all if you're running a
business i've been
okay
i've been uh i've been running a
business for so long i forget the the
residential side of it i apologize
you do have to be careful and there are
hoops to jump through and i i recommend
people actually
create some business so that they get
certain amount of uh
tax leniency
generates yes and electricity bill
the amount of electricity it pays
it pays them back for the solar so
there's
they don't have electricity bill and
it doesn't cost you anything
well that's amazing
he said what he said was that there's a
company in california that if you will
install their if you'll allow them to
install their technology on your house
you can uh uh they own the tech they own
the uh the alternative solar technology
um and they get their their refund off
of the amount of uh money that's
generated from uh the the electric
company buying electricity back but
we're kind of getting off subject here
we could talk about that um what i'm
saying is that if you do the research
and we did we did a lot of this we we
ran all the numbers in uh
in in at the university this year um
it's it's actually easier to go off grid
than it is now than it ever has been in
the history of this country so very
important stuff here um
who was i talking to about the about
bedini or assuming uh sterling cycle
engines today
oh he's not here
well i guess he didn't get the memo on
when it started my apologies um
hydrogen is very interesting gas and
we'll talk about this uh more but you
can use sterling cycle engines to uh
to power hydrogen
and you don't have to uh you don't have
to um
once again you won't have to buy propane
you won't have to buy cooking fuels and
stuff like that how many people have
played with the bidini motor
how many people actually got one just
the little tiny one to actually run i've
played that
um
it doesn't create a whole lot of power
does it
but
what if you had it just creates enough
to light a light bulb
okay
well that's all this thing takes to run
a light bulb and that's 20 liters a
minute if you had five of those things
going and you had all going into you
know one or two of these things
you can generate your own
power you can generate your own hydrogen
off of the bidini motor and these this
is this is paradigm shifting stuff we're
not going to try and run the house we're
not going to try and run the building
we just need a little bit to boost
ourselves along and we'll talk about
boosting
vacuum is really interesting vacuum is
to me
the other side of the equation you've
got the einsteinian physics big powerful
explosions and blowing things up
vacuum is the the uh
the the redheaded steph child okay
what you see here this is a vacuum
aspirator pump anybody played with one
of those in chemistry
we boiled water in 10 minutes with one
of those things using just flowing water
okay
that was the other thing for building
this device is it can run off of vacuum
vacuum assisted
here's the problem with vacuum assisted
as it is now what type of hydra or what
type of uh
catalyst solution do you guys use
in your hydrogen
potassium hydroxide sodium hydroxide
which one
okay um
here's the deal with the vacuum if you
have a bubbler
in a vacuum
you will suck the water out okay
you will eventually pull the water out
of this and we did this on a friend's
race car okay a little he he built this
little uh
uh formula atlantic race car eats
porsches and and uh and ferraris
for breakfast it's a toyota celica but
his vacuum on his air intake was so
powerful it sucked all the water out of
the uh out of the tube but boy howdy
it got great it was getting 40 miles to
the gallon a formula atlantic race car
getting 40 miles to the gallon because
of the vacuum assist on the hydrogen but
here's the deal you can't use ko knoh no
you can't use any of the hydroxides
because they don't like metal
so what you have to do is you have to
create a new catalyst
do not play with uh
baking soda
it will eat up your plates it's a bad
idea anyway
so vacuum is one of the most uh one of
the most underrated technologies in our
uh
in our world this is a picture of a of a
new advanced uh sterling cycle engine
very powerful this is a vertical
windmill technology i'm a real big fan
of vertical windmills because vertical
windmills
do not produce the high pitch hum that
drives people insane and liquefies your
organs
okay
how many people live anywhere near one
of those giant horizontal blade
windmills
have anybody heard the sound coming off
those things it's like living underneath
a jet engine that never goes away okay
this is the this is the answer to that
technology
this year i got involved with a family
that has that is uh funding the
development of large-scale horizon or
vertical windmill technology and what it
is is it can go inside of a grain silo
okay
you can't tell it's there it goes inside
the grain silo the air goes in through
it through ducts it's more efficient
than
conventional windmill technology and
it can go up to
130 mile per hour winds okay
the absolute max on a on a horizontal
windmill is is 60 miles per hour
but that you know we lose our power
curve at that point so these things can
go up to 130 miles an hour and they're
silent they're beautiful if you and
anyone can build this you can go out and
get a squirrel cage fan
for 20 bucks or pull it out of the
junkyard put that together put on it
i've done this it works put on a little
alternator and power your hydrogen
device it works it's great
um
hydrogen for heat we're going to talk
about hydrogen for heat hydrogen is not
just for boosting cars anymore
this is a cool little deal hey john
could i get video number one please
thank you very much i'll talk about this
in a minute
this is a little experiment you can find
it on youtube
um
i was too uh wrapped up to record my
experiments with this
um but
what you see don't don't do sound no
sound on this one
what we're going to see is a is a is a
mr heater device
um
powered by hydrogen okay
mr heater is a little as a little
heating device you hook up to a propane
tank uh not this one
that's uh that's number
that's number three i think go to number
one
go to video number one please
we'll get to that don't worry
it'll be fun
there we go video number one
there we are
okay so here's the propane
there's a propane running
and that's what the mr heater looks like
anybody works with anybody using mr
heater at all
okay
now we're adding the hho that's one
liter a minute
you see the change in there
he's going to take away here in a second
and there goes back down
thank you very much john um what he's
doing here is he's boosting hydrogen
just like we're boosting cars that you
know that we were talking about before
in this in this video he's boost
assuming not hydrogen he's boosting
propane
okay now propane is one of the cleanest
burning fuels but it still has issues
and by adding yeah let's turn off that
other one
thank you
by adding hydrogen we can make that
propane burn completely clean we can
make it burn hotter but what they're
they're they're kind of going about it
wrong they can melt their device if
they're not careful so
what we do
that's the end
uh back oh here i'll get it i'll get it
okay
um what we have down here in the corner
is our regulator device now you can go
out and you can buy an expensive
regulator or you can get one of these
this is a regulator goes on a propane
tank
and you can control that so fine you can
control it down
to um milliliters per hour okay and i'll
pass this around
here we go
that's the system i use to control i
don't use a mr heater i use a uh
i use a a blow a blower furnace instead
but that's a system that i use to
control
uh just a tiny amount of propane what
happens is
the hydrogen burns the propane
instead of just the bur the propane
burning in the air and it boosts the
efficiency
and you use you use a tenth of the
amount of uh amount of propane um that
you would normally use and so you're
running off of a little solar panel you
run this you generate the hydrogen here
run it into there and you have
practically free heat coming out of your
uh coming out of your propane generator
but like i said you use this little
device here and you can
dial down the propane so much you just
got a little tiny trickle
and the real deal is done by the is done
by the hydrogen okay and it works
put it into my shop i'm i'm going to use
it this winter it's going to be the sole
source of heat in my shop this winter
because it's it's been a really exciting
summer
uh what you do is you'll see that
person's hand right there
there is a little opening in that uh in
that heater there's a little opening
that allows the propane to mix with the
oxygen
as it goes up the deal and into the into
the burner
what you do is you tape off one side and
you put your hydrogen in there okay
adjust your you turn it on full blast
with your with your propane
start putting your hydrogen in and then
just back that off until you get it to
the proper temperature and boom you're
using solar power generating hydrogen
heating your place yes
yes oh i apologize i am so sorry
everything that i've talked about to
this point is brown's gas hho
i will talk about the pure hydrogen in
just a minute i apologize thank you for
bringing that up okay this is
hydrogen and oxygen hho bronze gas
whatever you want to call it um i'll
talk about the pure stuff here in a
minute
okay moving right along
uh we're still on hydrogen for heating
these are the possibilities that we all
have
none of this is experiment oh well i
mean it's experiment none of this is
theoretical
all of anyone can do it this is how i'm
like i said this is how i'm heating my
shop this year i might even heat my
house with it because i've got radiant
subfloor heating and run it through
heating water and and use uh that system
okay
um
we're gonna heat air now anybody played
with brown's gas at all you create a you
create a flame about this big okay you
got the little torch here and the flames
coming out there and you can run your
hand through it and stuff you're not
really running your hand through it
okay
you're not touching it it will burn
through you what is happening is
that the torch
is literally burning the air
as it flows out away from the tip okay
and when you move it
that torch the
the real fire goes down to about
half an inch
and then when you stop
it goes back through so if you hold your
hand in front of it you will burn
through your hand but you can move your
hand unlike unlike uh
oxygen acetylene or regular hydrogen
torch
which will cut your hand or burn your
hand in half
it takes a few moments for it to index
there another interesting thing about
hydrogen is
that
brown's gas will index itself to
whatever it's burning through so if you
have it there and you're waving it
around in the air and you take a
measurement on it
you are running about 180 degrees that's
how you that's one of the indicators of
decent bronze gas okay you take that and
you put it into water and it won't boil
the water because it indexes itself to
whatever you're working on however
you fill this thing with water and you
take that torch and you put it on the
bottom of this thing you're going to
have boiling water in seconds
i've tried it it's fun
okay
it indexes itself to whatever
uh it comes up against and uh what was
it ned eric eric uh eric white who was
the gentleman that talked about brown's
gas couple years back
oh
static
it's an avalanche
of electromagnetic energy anybody
tracking the solar flares this year
we've had computers wiped out by the
solar flares it's been fun
dealing with that
because it's not like you could you've
got a surge protector that doesn't do
anything it's electrostatic pressure in
the air it's great
which is good for free energy but not so
good for computers telecommunications
sound systems you know that type of
thing okay
um so what we have to do is we have to
find a material
if we're gonna heat air we're gonna have
to find a material that we can heat up
and heat the air secondarily
what anybody play with brown's gas know
what doesn't disintegrate under
browns under bronze gas anybody
okay there's a couple of things i can't
say them all because
it's technology that i didn't develop
and and such but i can say cast iron
cast iron does not disintegrate under
bronze gas
certain types of silica ferrosilica
you can heat it you can you can nearly
melt it but it will not disintegrate so
you take here's what i did
in my experiments
i took a little aluminum tube like this
punch some little holes into it
put a uh
suspended a
excuse me
a
cast iron bolt in the center of this
thing
put my torch in there
heated the cast iron bolt and then i had
a little this isn't the one i i left it
at home because it was too big of an
apparatus
and
pumped air through an impeller fan up
through this thing and son of a gun
i've got to air temperatures that are
reaching seven eight hundred degrees
coming out the top here okay just from a
height little hydrogen torch and i'm
only running you know about two liters a
minute through it which equates out to
about uh 200 to 300 watts of power and
i've got 600 degrees of air
okay i mean i mean it's like it's like a
heat gun for crying out loud but i'm not
running 30 amps off of or excuse me 15
amps off of the deal i'm only running
about 250 300 watts
so what we've done is we've managed to
find a way to use the inherent
characteristics of the brown's gas
to perform something that wouldn't
normally uh wouldn't normally be
feasible if you try and do this with
compressed hydrogen you will not it will
not work your power to uh heat ratio is
is way out of proportion but because we
because brown's gas indexes itself to
whatever you're putting it against
that you can use you have to be very
careful that you don't move it off to
the side otherwise you get a stream of
brown's gas coming out the side of your
torch it burns through aluminum pretty
darn quick yeah how about carbon
it doesn't burn carbon but carbon has a
carbon has a nasty habit of popping and
blasting off and you have to deal with
the carbon uh the carbon emissions not
carbon emissions actually thank you for
bringing that up because i'm going to
jump on a soapbox here
um
carbon emissions are not the
terrible thing greenhouse gases that
we'd like to believe that they are
okay
in one earthquake eruption
in
um
in iceland released more carbon
greenhouse gases the entire than the
entire world produces in a year okay one
eruption
and how many how many of those we have
around the world today what you really
have to think about when you start
thinking about greenhouse or assuming
emissions and bad things for the
environment
volatile organic compounds
those are the killer vocs
and unburned hydrocarbons don't even
care about carbon monoxide carbon
dioxide okay
not even an issue
it's like anything with the government
like we're in the middle of a debt
crisis right
no man i'll i'll share that stuff off
the record later but anything that
people say oh my god look how bad this
is it's a rope-a-dope look at this look
at this
i'm going to take you from the other
side so
think about that anything that is big in
the media start looking to the things
that nobody's mentioning okay
so we're seeing this carbon monoxide
carbon dioxide oh my god it's so
terrible
look at what's really happening voc is
getting inside of our brain lowering the
lowering our our ability to think our
ability to reason
unburned hydrocarbons going in there and
messing up our organ function those are
the real issues we don't care about that
stuff this is five years of research
into the uh
into that whole deal and it's been an
interesting trip okay so we've got
we don't vaporize uh um cast iron so
we're heating this thing we're pulling
out 600 degrees
i've seen people playing with this on
the internet and it's absolutely
terrifying to me because they're heating
up
they're using hydrogen they're heating
up things like copper copper
it's hard to cut copper with brown's gas
they're heating up things like copper
they're heating different elements
they're heating carbon and they're
hooking it up to a computer fan and
they're blowing it out into their room
how many people weld in here
okay what i mean you put that torch on
the middle what starts happening it
starts getting smoke you're breathing
fumes you're breathing uh you're
breathing carbon because it's oxygen
acetylene you're breathing steel
particles you're breathing whatever
you're cutting off okay whatever you're
cutting through whatever you're welding
whatever you're doing you're breathing
that stuff and uh boy howdy parkinson's
anybody
heavy metal poisoning metal fume fever
oh that's a fun one
okay these idiots are literally heating
up something and blowing it directly out
into the room this is bad really bad
don't ever play with it that's why i
higgs a heat exchanger okay you take
this
you run it around to an inner cooler off
of a dodge cummings turbo diesel run it
around there got your fan in the
intercooler blowing out the blowing
through there and run the whole thing
back through a bucket of water into your
into your fan system and you trap all of
those fumes in the water and you don't
actually breathe it
the the heat exchanger is the equivalent
of these things
to make certain no uh
no sodium hydroxide gets into your
engine okay this is very very important
so if you're going to do work with heat
use a heat exchanger
okay
this this has nothing to do with the mr
heater because that is actually burning
of the fuel and and a catalytic response
so you don't really care about that but
if you're heating things up use a heat
exchanger okay we're going to move on
i'm going to talk about some of the the
possibilities with the browns gas um
anybody familiar with gasification
okay what's the what is the efficiency
of an internal combustion engine anybody
14 25
what's that
27. so that they change all over the
place uh whatever engine that 5.6 in the
gmc yukon is 14
um the uh the high efficiency hondas are
are 27 to 30. um they now get uh they're
getting
57 percent efficiency off of the toyota
prius but that's because it's the most
efficient way to get power to the
engines but we won't get into that um
we now have the the ability
off-the-shelf technology
to run engines at 90 efficiency using
gasification they do it down in the
jungles of south america africa stuff
like that in remote locations where
nobody talks about it we're going to do
cool stuff back over here away
gasification is the way they do that
okay you can boost the efficiency
basically what gasification is it says i
have a fuel
i don't have any fuels up here i have a
fuel
that
needs to have its energy released so i'm
going to heat it up in a certain way and
i'm going to release the energy okay you
can do it with coconut you can do it
with wood you can do it with anything as
a matter of fact all the new stoves all
the new types of stoves that you can buy
they're not wood burning stoves they're
they're cool gasification units they
just look like wood burning stoves okay
very cool stuff uh some of them eighty
percent efficient i just put in two of
them in my house pretty cool stuff um
could you get john i need them to play
video number two uh i'm gonna show you a
little video on gasification and how to
use
brown's gas to release the hidden energy
potential
in something now
what you've got to understand is when
you burn something you are you're
combusting you're combusting the uh the
substance could you queue up video
number two please thank you um
you're combusting the substance
excuse me
um
yep there we go
but if you add enough hydrogen and
oxygen to something
anything absolutely anything can become
a fuel okay
and what he's got in here is a soda can
filled with wood chips okay
and he's lighting it with a propane
burner
uh you can see the propane burner down
there
i want you to see how long it takes for
this this uh soda can filled with wood
chips to start to gasify okay
you can see some gas fumes coming out of
there
pretty slowly
these guys are really cool knowledge
publications uh roy mcallister's group
talking about hydrogen
what's up
oh okay um
pretty cool group check out their
website they don't like hydrogen on
demand
they've got all sorts of mathematics and
flute music telling me why everything
that i do is impossible
okay
but they have a lot of information we'll
go to another one of their videos
um what he's doing is he's heating up
that can
and i want to see how long this is
taking okay
um
i'm just trying to release the release
the the hidden gases in that wood and
let us burn more efficiently
can you jump to a jump to this no no i'm
sorry no he's gonna he's gonna light it
now
there we go
you can't see it very well in this light
but it's actually
he's actually got about six or eight
inches of flame coming off of there
and that is that is the most efficient
burn of wood on the planet now what is
interesting is if you apply a bronze gas
flame to the bottom of that
you will generate that heat in seconds
okay there isn't the waiting there isn't
all that you'll generate that heat in
seconds
especially if you have it in a little
cast iron cup or a uh
some type of crucible that isn't going
to disintegrate
seconds and you'll be you'll be
generating the heat oh wow that thing's
like nothing's like a foot tall
okay
so
this is another possibility of
generating heat you can cook on that
okay this is a system of using brown's
gas imagine that instead of the propane
using brown's gas to cook your food on
okay
and it's the most efficient system let's
say that's literally just a handful of
pellets you can't do that in a fireplace
you can only do that with a gasification
process there is a friend of mine that
is retrofitting a uh
a
resort in the south china sea
and he is using
high efficiency gasifiers
and they use coconut husks okay
literally the byproduct of their their
coconut industry in in town
power is is is powering about 50
of an ecological resort down there in
the on the island okay
all their their lights their their air
conditioners all of that all that's
coming from biomass
gasification units yes
they do finally get consumed but when
they're consumed they are pure carbon
which
yes you can use it you can use it in
filtration systems um sand carbon bio
filtration systems oh they're awesome
they can take almost everything out of
uh they can take sewage practically and
turn it into drinkable water using
carbon and sand great stuff back there
another question
mm-hmm
right what they're using is is just a
regular little propane cook stove but
what we would do is we would put uh the
torch against the bottom of it to
get the get the heat you couldn't use a
can this is a demonstration you would
never do this
in in reality you could use a you could
use a coffee can
we have done that for alchemical
experience you can use a coffee can
um thank you you can shut that one off
and go to the second one or number three
if you would please number three
thank you so much
um
that's a little shameless plug they're
uh they're selling their book you buy it
it's a great thing to do
but it will discourage people from doing
on-demand hydrogen so remember that
this is another gasification system
um
this is a gentleman
uh i'll just let you read it this i'll
just step back and be quiet here for a
second so just watch this real quick
uh you could but it's in japanese
[Music]
that's the back
the video in the background is still
playing
can you turn off the other
[Music]
is
so what this gentleman done has done
basically is he's created a system that
you can recycle
recycle waste plastic okay
and i'll talk about the hydrogen aspect
of it here in a moment a friend of
mine's actually rebuilding this all of
this is open source
okay you can buy this device for 12
grand
or you can build it yourself it's all
open source all he's done is he's
created a system
that he's created a small uh
cost-effective system
and what it is is it's the same deal as
the as the the gasification
he pulls a vacuum on
a chamber
we can just use this as the uh
as an example oh this is fun
this is straight out of his machine from
a from um glass or plastic bottles and a
styrofoam container okay
um he pulls a vacuum on that on that
chamber
heats various parts of it to different
temperatures one part of it is 400 one
part of it is 300 one part of it's like
200.
say again
exactly he's cracking it but he's doing
it in a but he's doing it on a small
scale
then the vapors go across and
re-recondense in the uh
in the um in the water now they're
playing it down
but there's methane
released from this process
well methane is the same thing as
natural gas you could take that off and
burn it again so what you have basically
is something that looks like this they
can't show it in there but you fill this
with plastic
you heat
various parts you pull a vacuum on it
heat various parts of it and everything
starts to break down because there's no
oxygen in there for it to burn
everything goes off as a vapor and
recondenses in the water okay friend of
mine is building this in utah right now
we're going to we wanted to have it
available here but
his schedule didn't permit it but
essentially it is a system whereby
a community of people
never needs to throw away
plastic ever again you don't even have
to take it to the recycler you can turn
it into the very oil
or the very fuel that you need in your
cars okay using plastic and browns gas
see what he's using he's pulling about a
thousand watts that that machine takes
about uh one kilowatt hour to run okay
and you have to hook it up to the grid
and it's very and it pulls down hard you
can do the same thing with the hydrogen
because that's very simple you just have
you just have three different torches
at varying distances to heat up the to
heat up your chamber at different levels
i didn't realize there was oil on that
so
um
that's what we're doing i supplied the i
just applied the hydrogen torch and he's
building the uh essentially it's a big
autoclave unit yes
did you say solar
you could do that and uh i i was going
to mention
um
you can melt steel with it but it's
what he said was that if you have if you
have solar panel if you have solar um
condensers either a uh either uh either
a dish or a lens can be used you can
generate temperatures in excess of a
thousand degrees using just the sun and
this is all possible
if you have a
inch by 60 inch fresnel lens you can
mount that into a frame and generate
over 800 watts of power okay
using simply you simply using the sun
and the lens
40 percent of our energy in this country
goes to heating water
that's all
and all of that can be done by the sun
all right solar water heating panels we
did that in my in my alternative power
class we we demonstrated how um how a
home or a business or the entire country
could literally cut out 40 of their
electric bill using just the sun not the
inefficient photovoltaics but sun heat
here
and that works and i encourage people to
do that here's my issue with that
i always see things worst case scenario
is there a scenario that we have seen
that is possible that you would not see
the sun you would not have the power
come on somebody
cloudy nuclear winter okay
volcanoes thank you were you from europe
oh okay um
night time all right all of these are
all these are huge issues that we that
we that we can face um
i
i set about
uh developing the idea for technology
that you could do inside of a cave if
you could not live outside in the air
and i know that's a little bit extreme
but here we have fukushima
all right and we're dealing with here
let me get it i'll get it
um
and we're dealing with a huge amount of
radiation
in uh falling on our plants
contaminating our the milk supply
the first of all the rain water in san
francisco as of a month ago was 800
times the epa maximum for radiation all
coming from fukushima media blackout
the milk
supply more than more than more than 100
times the the allowable radiation media
blackout
okay i have friends in tokyo
all right they're saying nobody's died
yet from fukushima
but
what's radiation poisoning the walking
dead
yes sir
one and a half million babies in two
years from chernobyl what how much more
is fukushima than chernobyl yeah it's
like 300 what's up
at least at least
anyway i'm not trying to be a fear
monger i don't do that i'm giving you
guys tools and solutions radiation is a
boogeyman kept around by the by the
governments in the scientific community
there are five different ways of
eliminating radiation i could think up
off the top of my head
okay
so the research is out there you can do
it as a matter of fact i live in
colorado our res our our uh our
background radiation should be five
times more than it is right now but it's
not do you know why
pine trees
pine trees give off negative ions
negative ions neutralize radiation drop
it out of the sky
okay
i would be concerned if if if uh
if a nuclear bomb went off in las vegas
living in colorado i would be relatively
concerned
but i know
so many different ways to get rid of
radiation poisoning both in myself but
the issue is that you deal with it
coming from the sky
if it comes down all my friends with
gardens outside
it can all be they can all be
contaminated like that you've got to put
your gardens under under
greenhouses put them inside there's many
many many different ways using this
technology you can you can generate as
much light as you need
to uh to feed your gardens inside so
just something to think about
yes sir
i wasn't talking about the sun i was
talking about either
are we there
i was talking about radiation fallout
radiation fallout from the sky from
either fukushima or any other nuclear
accident we've had three in the past six
months you know that's kind of oh thank
you very much um
also we deal with a lot of uh you know
we deal with the chemtrails we deal with
we're seeing metals falling from the sky
for fronting out loud go out and put a
bathtub out there seat it with a little
bit of water and start collecting the
dew on on heavy due morning
and see what see what uh lands there
analyze it you'll start finding chromium
hexane and als or assuming
hexavalent chromium thank you um
stuff like that falling from our skies
don't put your gardens outside cover
them up
okay
we've seen the gasification
yes
okay in that uh the process of the
gasification of oil what you get is a
hydrocarbon-based liquid that can either
be put directly into a diesel truck
if you use different if you use more
complex plastics you get a thicker based
oil that you can actually use for
viscosity and lubrication
and you get the byproduct of
methane gas which they downplay
but we don't we like that because we can
use that for heating and cooking our
food
so
what you've seen is the process
right there
where you can use brown's gas
recycle plastic and create something in
a community
that uh will benefit the environment and
keep make you guys more self-sufficient
okay
so in any type of scenario this is this
is a very very key
okay
um
i went i went back to university i
started studying some welding processes
so i could understand how hydrogen fit
in with
fitting with welding and what i found
was that uh
our welding shop there it's it's
arguably one of the best welding
programs in the entire western united
states
we go through 2 000 a week in fuel gas
alone
okay two thousand that's eight thousand
dollars a month in um
uh
propylene we don't use acetylene because
acetylene is too high in carbon now
industry standards going to propylene we
use
through two thousand dollars a month in
propylene which is about half of what
we'd use if we used uh
acetylene because propylene is cheaper
oh i'm out again
okay i'll just speak up
um
what we found was that uh we could we
could substitute hydrogen what i found
in this shop was that we could
substitute hydrogen for about 500 bucks
a week
of their fuel gas bill still need it
still need uh propylene for certain
things
thank you
uh we still need propylene for certain
things but we can
use uh brown's gas for scarfing scarfing
is uh it's it's the most expensive form
of oxygen acetylene cutting it
[Music]
it cuts off metal uh
metal pieces that are too large to grind
off use a scarfing torch and cut it off
brown's gas lends itself incredibly well
to that because it burns through
anything it cuts through the cuts
through the steel you just add a little
bit of oxygen to it and boom you're
using we could save 500 bucks of 500
bucks a week just in the scarfing
process
cutting some cutting still needs to be
done with oxygen propylene
but a lot of it can be done with uh with
with the hydrogen and heat treating oh
heat treating is so much fun oh man it
is so cool you can take because brown's
gas is implosive
you take the torch
and you put it on a single spot
like right there
i can heat treat that one location
and nothing else gets solid and that's
that's that location gets incredibly hot
and i'll pass this around in a minute
for another example
but uh very important stuff
we're running we're i'm taking too much
time because i want to get to the fun
stuff um
the other thing is it's very clean
because it's burning uh because it's
clean burning we're not releasing a lot
of the gases
that would that would
uh that would normally uh
curse it's a very clean alternative
um how much can you say we're saving uh
maybe we could save about 500 bucks a
week by switching over to profiling our
hydrogen instead of uh
just constantly using propylene moon
based scenario that's my word for uh you
know what's the worst case scenario you
gotta live in a cave you can't be
outside
this is absolutely key for rebuilding
civilization we'll talk about that a
little bit more
another system for uh for the hydrogen
is boosting the boosting generators and
large power plants
a friend of mine is over in the
philippines right now
ninety percent if you buy something that
says made in the philippines or made in
one of those places
90 percent of their power comes from
dirty burning sulfur emitting diesel
fuel
okay
we are literally
more emissions come from the philippines
than the cars in the united states just
from their power plants okay if you buy
from them that's where it's coming from
so
he's over there and he's got
he's got the most god-awful units ever
made they're one step ahead of the
mason jars with a little wires wrapped
into it which are little tiny bombs hand
grenades hydrogen hand grenades
but their work his stuff is working he's
got the cool little design he's got it
in a plastic box they're they're they're
boosting efficiency by 15
and they're cutting out 50 of the
emissions
and he got in and he made some friends
and they'll be
about 50 percent of the the power plants
over in the philippines will be
converted over in the next three years
okay so that's really exciting okay
they're not they're not as efficient
but
they are they are working and that
because they're burning it's the clean
alternative they're burning the fuels
that would normally be admitted as waste
um it's it's working pretty well
but what he's doing is he's self-running
it he's taking the power from their
generator
powering his his hydrogen unit and
sending it back into the uh sending it
back into his air intake
that's good it's okay it's what
everybody's doing it's what you do when
you run a car it's what you do when you
run put it on a truck but let me show
you something that's better okay can we
turn on this uh this ninja on this thing
thank you um
a friend of mine bought this unit right
here and let me bring it here today
no no the ninja john
the ninja to see this one
yeah
okay
better turn that off
um a friend of mine bought this unit
because like i said he lives in the
mountains
run we figured it out using his solar
panels and his generator he can run
ninety percent uh savings on his diesel
generator and and completely disconnect
from the grid he'll be self running it's
it's very very cool and he doesn't have
to have any batteries
that's the problem with solar
and and wind power is the battery system
there's no efficient way of storing the
energy but with this
we store the energy as a as a
combustible gas that doesn't lose its
efficiency it's fantastic yes
what's that
he said that you can store energy in the
super capacitors and that and that's
fantastic but i don't have the money for
a super capacitor
i
we'll we'll we'll see where they go
looking forward to seeing where the
technology goes hey john
okay
oh no problem okay so i'll show you that
in a second here um where was i here
okay anyway what we found what i'm about
to show you this is one of the very cool
things that i learned this with this
this year
you can um what i'm about to show you is
how to
run a generator strictly on water itself
i don't believe the the water you know
oh we're running you know running this
car and water and stuff like that i
haven't seen anybody actually prove it
yet
but there are some tricks that you can
do it using this technology
and using a vapor
injection
you can actually run an engine on water
and this is what this is what we did
took 300 watts worth of solar panels
okay
300 okay
there we go took 300 watts worth of
solar panels
running something like this
and
a little
um
fountain vaporizer anybody seen those
things the they've got the they've got
the blue glass deal and and the vapor
kind of rolls out
yes the ultrasonic exciters they're they
they vaporize the water and they create
little little uh um
vape cloud vapors in in your little
fountain
what you do is you take one of those and
you put it into a five gallon bucket
this is what we did we put into a five
gallon bucket
we ran the air intake through the five
gallon of a diesel generator diesel
generator
the air intake through a five gallon
bucket
with a vaporizer in the bottom
vaporizing the water
and ran that to the air intake and then
put the hydrogen right there from a
solar panel
into the the into the into the diesel
generator the reason why we use diesel
is because diesels
they don't care where the com where the
uh
where
the spark ignition is because they don't
have a spark okay
if you use gasoline you have to tear out
the ignition you have to tear out the
spark
the the uh excuse me the magneto telling
you when the spark is and you have to
put in a new circuit so forget about
gasoline diesel generator
use the uh
five gallon bucket generating the the uh
the fog the air goes through to the
diesel generator put the hydrogen there
the whole thing's powered off of solar
and what you have is a voltage
multiplier
we've got 12 volts 300 watts coming off
the solar panel generating the hydrogen
in the vapor going into
a 5 000 watt diesel generator okay
we're not over unity we're
there is over unity i've seen 10 of them
the last five years but
what we're doing is we're running on
water and what this system here is
is
a friend of mine ordered this to go into
his diesel generator so he can run his
facility in the mountains
uh we don't have oh
that's why i got the flashlight
we've got to get through all of this so
i can get to the really exciting stuff
because this is boring um what we have
here is
gas coming out of the of the generator
feeding
the uh excuse me
the reservoir
and uh
excuse me it's a reservoir and also the
first level of safety
so it bubbles through there and washes
out all of its sodium hydroxide so it
stays in the system
then the gas goes
down here i don't know if you can see it
no you can't see it very well there's a
hose that leads the water back to the
back to the generator so what you get is
a cycle of gas and water
water returning gas and water water
returning
then you come off the top of that
drop down here to the bottom of this
side which is your first stage of
bubbler
and what happens is the
the gas goes through you've got about
halfway full of water here the gas
bubbles through that and all the rest of
your sodium hydroxide gets washed out
and then your
the fuel gas comes out the top and goes
to your generator
all right
so that's a that's a that's the bare
bones basic system right here
what's really cool about this is i
figured out how to
uh
i don't have to punch holes in the shell
at all
i have ac input argument dc input 120
volts positive here
negative here
and you don't have any holes in your
generator at all everything is
completely contained
real neat little system anyone can do it
i'll teach you how to do it
just weld a couple plates to the inside
of the inside of your
stainless steel plate and bolted
together
fast easy and it's bomb proof i cut my
teeth on
the oil wells in southern california oil
wells and and diesel over the road
trucks there's no conditions on this
planet that are worse than those two 130
degrees in the air in bakersfield
california standing next and corrosive
environment standing next to those oil
pumps
they they eat the the stuff that comes
out of the ground eats steel for
breakfast
and so
this is the best system that i could
figure out how to put together you see
the dry cells on the internet they're
great for experimenting they will not
last in the field they will not last in
a harsh environment um
excuse me we can talk about spacing and
all that but basically i followed the uh
i followed the bob voice method of
eighth inch spacing
2.34 volts per cell
and uh
one quarter of an amp per square inch
one quarter of an amp per square inch is
the rule
if you go over that you will start
destroying your plates okay
so let me repeat that eighth inch
spacing
2.34 volts
per cell maximum
and one quarter of an amp per square
inch on the plate so
like this if we have the entire thing
this is a 6x6 plate
if we use the entire plate as a surface
we could only go to nine amps on this
plate
okay
if you start going over that you will
break down your cell or you will break
down your your metal now i get people
say well what if i put in frequencies
and i can go up to 40 amps
okay
follow the rules all right and i'll tell
you why
if you run that thing
for six months and we've done this
you run it for that thing for six months
you'll form a crystalline layer on the
surface of the metal and those plates
will stop producing hydrogen
okay
so if you follow the rules you will get
a system and i've got systems have been
running for five years now
okay some of them running for 24 hours a
day seven days a week for three years
straight
316 stainless
i did i worked with bob boyce a while
back i wish he was here i don't know why
he's not here um i worked with bob boyce
a while back and he said i believe that
304 is going to be less efficient than
316 but i just don't know i immediately
went home bought some 304 and threw it
in to the same system and i lost 25
efficiency
so
i have not because i want to focus on
what everyone has access to and anyone
can use
316 stainless
every once in a while they get
they get l but
i just always buy 316. i buy the
cheapest 316 possible
so i don't know exactly what grade
everyone like i said every once in a
while it's 316l so
that's my that's my standby yes
um here's the secret
see this pvc
this is cpvc it's uh
um it'll go up to 120 degrees
if you're up to 120 degrees in your cell
something's wrong um water does not boil
at a hundred or so maybe 220 degrees
water does not boil at 212 degrees in
these units
water boils at 140 degrees in these
units
if you're boiling water you're wasting
energy and producing vapor
bad bad bad you have to this is why when
i was building units in uh for the the
uh the
oil wells in southern california i
learned this the hard way
really hard way at 140 degrees water
starts boiling in this system and then
you're pumping water vapor instead of
hydrogen and oxygen and bad things are
going to happen so you have to develop a
system you have to develop a unit that
can run
below 140 degrees preferably no more
than 120 your optimum is going to be
98.6 interestingly enough okay
i built units that can be immersed in
water
because actually in the air the air
itself around these engines in southern
california was 130 to 140 degrees
and so we actually had to water cool the
entire thing
and that's that's a pain but but you can
do it and it led to amazing efficiencies
yes
the gauge doesn't matter because you're
not going to burn them up
but if you want but if you get down
below 20 or 22 gauge you start getting
flexing
and when you get imagine that your
plates are this far apart and you get a
flex in there suddenly they're in like
this and they're this far apart and you
get a disparity between your your uh
amperages and that's going to start
burning it up this is why i do not like
round
tubular units okay i'll show you some in
a little bit but
round tubular units you cannot match
your your amperages
so your amperage on the inside is going
to be umpteen your amperage on the
inside is going to be
9 amps
and your average on the outside is going
to be a lot or a lot less than that so
you're not getting equal
equal variation we put we bought some
some very popular of your units we ran
around the full power and literally when
we opened that thing up after a week it
fell in half
because the the round you cannot match
your your uh your amperages so i will
always go with the uh i'll always go
with this with the plates
now in these i went with round plates
okay
they're round plates i had them cut out
on a on a water jet very simple to do
and oh i i didn't talk about the spacers
these spacers are made
out of the cpvc
i put the took a piece of cv c pvc put
it on a lathe and just shaved off eighth
inch spacers oh god that takes a long
time
really long time then i discovered that
i could use my three freedom three axes
cnc mill put a little cutter on that
thing and just cut off
used used a diamond grinding wheel cut
them off and create all the spacers trim
them and then just put them in place
that's the easiest way to do it i don't
care about rubber rubberizing the whole
thing and making it completely sealed
i what i found was that the efficiency
levels
don't match the amount of money and
energy you put into it so it doesn't
really matter just put those cpvc rings
in there and push them together i create
little springs in here out of folded
stainless steel so that when i jam that
thing together the entire inside of this
box is in compression it's all in
compression so those those uh plates are
all held in place then you use a tet
then you use teflon spacers around the
outside a sheet of teflon you actually
put that in first and then load it with
your plates
teflon will go up to 500 degrees so if
somebody pours in
seawater in here it's not going to burn
itself up because it will go up to about
300 degrees if you pour seawater into
this thing
but that's another story we'll get to
that um
so the teflon will keep that from ever
happening so there's some some uh
secrets for the uh for the builders you
know the hydrogen builders in here like
i said 316 stainless i like 18 gauge
18 gauge is uh it's a good um
it stays it stays pretty stable and it's
cheap and it's easy to work if you go to
16 it's more expensive to cut stuff like
that i don't recommend people build
these for for their hydrogen devices i
recommend people build these because
these are indestructible these are fun
and i'll get to why i built this and why
it's sitting here
but
what's up
for sodium hydroxide it's always going
to be eighth inch
okay even george wiseman who pioneered
uh
the building of the generators went from
half inch down to eighth inch okay
because he found that uh bob boyce was
right it's more efficient to go
um
an eighth inch instead of a instead of a
half inch if you start going smaller
all of your parameters change your
voltage your maximum voltage changes
your maximum current changes
and your efficiency level changes
and that's in here and we'll get to that
all right moving right along can we go
back to the powerpoint john
the powerpoint please
oh
[Music]
okay thank you very much
all right so what i've just described is
a system of using solar power because
that way you don't have any parasitic
drag to boost your uh to boost a
generator or something like that use the
vapor for the octane see when you use
that little vapor generator
you're using the water as a fuel but
you're also using it to cool down the
explosion like i mentioned earlier
hydrogen oxygen the most powerful
destructive force in the galaxy
but it happens so fast it's gone now
okay and here i have to dispel something
else
brown's gas is implosive right
when you combust it it's an implosion
not an explosion
okay wow
tough crowd never mind um
that's that's a big thing everybody says
oh it's impulse it's not explosive and
you've seen pictures of them inflating
cans and stuff like that and nuclear
remediation by implosion
true bronze gas can do that
but it's a very powerful implosion
followed by a super powerful explosion
and i had a friend that actually wanted
to test this he had a syringe a little
glass syringe he was going to fill it
with brown's gas and then he was going
to light the end and he was going to
watch the plunger go in
no he's going to get shrapnel and
everything all over the place it's an
implosion followed by a powerful
explosion which interestingly enough is
exactly how they have to explode nuclear
bombs powerful implosion creating a
geometrical structure in the plasma of
the
plutonium followed by an incredibly
powerful explosion all right
same thing with the hydrogen
instantaneous implosion followed by a
powerful explosion when you see them
suck the water out
into a from a five gallon bucket into
the into the thing that they filled with
browns gas and and it sucks all the
water out and there's a vacuum over
there they've quenched the explosion
using the water
that's why it is
but please don't play around with
brown's gas thinking that you will see
an implosion
it's a good way to blow yourself up oh
somebody did that
four or five months ago some guy in
california figured he'd compress brown's
gas don't ever compress bronze gas it's
a good way to you know
go see jesus
go to church instead come on
okay
um
now the other thing that i built this
for was to was to experiment with vacuum
and this is
the only way
the only way you can use a vacuum
assisted system to boost your hydrogen
in the car
is if you do not use
sodium hydroxide or protect any type of
caustic solution i know that we're
getting really techy and technical and
we'll get to the fun stuff here
you know we're going to skip that
completely because we've been talking
too long okay
if you use a different catalyst you can
use vacuum assist and you will get
better gas from a vacuum assisted unit
than you will with brute force
electrolysis okay but with a vacuum
assisted unit
you use a different catalyst and we can
talk about that actually you can use my
gold you can use colloidal silver you
can use
spring water you can use all sorts of
fun stuff
and what you will find is that it will
separate and you don't care about having
to filter that out you can run that
right into your engine so you can hook
it up to a vacuum line on your engine
vacuum a sift separate and run that into
your intake and boom you will have a
much better gas
and a much better efficiency you'll use
a fraction of the power if you vacuum
assist it okay
so
very techy that's what that's another
thing that this was built for so i built
it's to withstand a vacuum because when
you vacuum it
did you know that that
large-scale industrial vacuum pumps have
a tendency to disintegrate why is that
anybody want to take a guess
large-scale vacuum pumps vacuum
pulling the vacuum out of things that
have liquid in them have a tendency to
disintegrate because of that most
terrible thing that we hear in the
hydrogen world hydrogen embrittlement
i'm not going to go into it but
literally when a vacuum pump
pumps all the air out it takes all the
water out of something too it takes all
the moisture out of the air
but in the process it separates the
oxygen and hydrogen
and it and its components become
embriddled by the pure hydrogen in that
system okay we really don't care about
vacuuming brittle or excuse me hydrogen
and brittle mint of this it's almost a
myth so we're not even going to talk
about it but in a vacuum pump you're
pulling out so much
hydrogen the parts becoming brittled and
the the pumps have a tendency to
disintegrate so that was the first clue
i said well why are they disintegrating
well
they're disintegrating because of
hydrogen bromine so does that mean that
a vacuum pulls
pulls out hydrogen and oxygen out of the
out of the water yeah it does that's why
vacuum assist is so awesome when it
comes to these hydrogen devices okay
so
you have to change the parameters you
can't use the sodium hydroxide you have
to use something else and that's when it
gets really exciting so we're going to
move on
now we're cooking with water or gas you
know what we don't have to we i've given
you all the all the parameters
what this in it we can use the uh
we can use
biogas
excuse me we can use gasification
cool off the fuel
boosting the same way we uh the same way
we boosted that uh
that that
mr heater do the same thing with your
cooking fuel okay that's what they're
doing actually in the in uh in one of
the resorts they're running solar
hydrogen they run it they boost their
propane they use less they use a tenth
to a 50th of the amount of propane
depending on the amount of heat they
need
and so literally the average person
could have a thousand gallon tank and
never fill that thing up the rest of
their lives if you use the if you use
the boosting with the hydrogen
all right
you know what that's all
i want to talk about the fun stuff okay
because this is what we're really here
for really cool stuff of course we have
to go back to 1910 to get to it but
this is a system
whereby a person can use
hydrogen and oxygen to create synthetic
gems
these gems were so perfect that the
people actually had to add impurities
to signify that they were not in fact
um
perfectly cut gems that they were
pulling out of mines
okay this is a ruby it's a synthetic
ruby
created using this system oxygen
hydrogen
um it's a process called flame fusion
i'll read it real quick flame fusion was
the first commercially successful method
of manufacturing synthetic gemstones
developed in 1902 excuse me by the
french
chemist auguste vernilli it was
primarily used to produce the ruby and
sapphire varieties of corundum as well
as the diamonds
stimulants rutile and strontium titanium
the principle of the process involves
melting a finely powdered substance
using an oxygen hydrogen flame and
crystallizing the melted droplets into a
brule i think that's brule
the process is considered to be the
founding step of modern industrial
crystal growth technology these are some
compared to that
this is a system
whereby we can actually
pardon me
we can actually start to use brown's gas
to move away from the idea of making
fuels
how much do how much do we actually use
per year in fuel i mean i use a lot i
drive about
about fifteen hundred to three thousand
miles a month
okay
so i use a lot how much do we use in
electricity my electricity to run my
shop is about about thirty dollars a
month
uh my house with all the various things
that we do there it's about 150 a month
so yeah it'd be nice to save that but is
that that much money in the long run
what this is is a system that we can
suddenly
start to see
independence not just energy
independence
not just
social independence but literally
monetary independence using brown's gas
technology so let's take a hypothetical
example let's say that everybody in this
section lived in the same neighborhood
right here
and we got a couple people over here who
are mechanically inclined and a couple
people over here who have time on their
hands and a couple people over there who
have some money bruce you're the winning
man
okay
so
um we've got the mechanically inclined
people in the community
building a hydrogen device and this
thing oh by the way that's just this
right here
oh it's passed around actually um
building this
we got a couple people with their time
on their hands and money guys you know
feed it into it and couple people with
their time in their hands just spend
their day
making gemstones oh and that gets more
fun than this this this is this is just
the beginning see the nth degree the fun
stuff we'll get there okay
you make gemstones where do you sell
gems
hey man i got a ruby
you buy some rubies
sapphires
got suppliers
diamonds
no
this is dangerous
quartzite arizona
largest rock and gem show in the world
everything that can trade hands in the
rock and gem world trades at the hands
of this place cash sales oh boy howdy
trades oh there's lots of that going on
you traded you traded gemstone as a
matter of fact
the largest platinum nugget the size of
my thumb nobody knows this it was
synthetic
the largest platinum nugget in the world
was sold at quartzite arizona for 57 000
it was made on a benchtop device similar
to what you're seeing right here it took
three hours to make
and he sold it at quartzite arizona for
57 000. okay
cash sale
you don't even have to do that
you go there
you trade
these now don't get greedy all right
i like greed but stupid greed is bad
okay
if you've got a gemstone that when it's
cut oh a fascinat a
faceting machine that you can buy you
guys with a lot of time in your hands
you got you guys with the money buy it
for these guys fastening machine
costs about a thousand
500 if you get it used real nice
fastening machine to to to facet the
gemstones if you've got a gem that
should be worth five thousand dollars
go out and be happy to sell it for a
thousand okay
because that allows you to turn it over
and
keep doing this and you'll fly under the
radar okay
go to courtside arizona make a trade
buy something that everybody likes
cathedrals okay
trade
the gem for the cathedral this happens
all the time so this is not something
weird that i'm talking about because i i
spent several years in quartzite
trade the gem for the cathedral sell the
cathedrals you get a monetary in you get
an income every month from selling the
cathedrals and you don't have this huge
income from the gemstones all at once
this is something to think about because
this allows all the people that are
playing with hydrogen to suddenly
start seeing the idea of financial
independence yes
cathedrals are uh um the beautiful
amethyst uh they're petrif are not
petrified but they're they're like
little they're like geodes only big
they're they're cathedrals that have
amethyst stones growing into them and
everything
um real big money you buy them at
courtside for eighty dollars you take
them to hollywood you sell them for 500
or a thousand
this way you trade and then you go out
and you sell them and you've got you've
got a way to make money that you kind of
fly under the radar well i'm throwing up
lots of red flags here i know that there
are people here reporting the
government
i'm not saying anything new but it
doesn't matter
okay here's the really here's here's
some really fun stuff
um
gold platinum and silver oh my
all right
who here has played with black sands
okay
who here knows that platinum content in
black sands is through the roof but the
energy required to get it out is
tremendous
okay
well
what do we have here
with the hydrogen
but a way to deliver huge amounts of
energy
with very little cost you hook it up to
a solar panel
and you don't have any
you don't have any uh or assuming you
don't have very much uh cost at all what
i did with this
this this does double duty at my place
it's a uh it actually mounts and i'll
pass this around right now it mounts in
here this is its water jacket water
comes in here goes out there so
eventually it'll be it'll it'll uh
it'll it'll serve the heat water but
what i did with this was put black sands
in here and start melting it
okay
melting the black sands and guess what's
the heaviest elements in the black sands
irons lighter than those guys
so it goes to the top vaporizes off and
the and the bigger stuff falls to the
bottom okay
so my friend with the detector over in
utah i hope that he gets here he's
developed a radical detector text things
at the distance he says oh yeah huge
amounts of platinum black sand i'm not
ready to sell it i'm just playing right
now
but essentially what you do here i'll
just pass this around
there you go please don't tip it over
and you can pull it apart but don't tip
it over because there's sand in it
what you'll do is you'll just create a
little
you just start heating it up and heating
it up and all the heavy elements will
drop to the bottom and the lighter
elements will go to the top and vaporize
okay yeah dude you have a question
oh okay
and so you can actually start to process
or like i said don't get greedy you
don't have to process hundreds of tons
okay
start doing that you start throwing red
flags up but if you process if you got
this thing going here powered off of the
sun
power off of solar power feeding in
there and it just sits there and
generates heat
just generates heat for three or four
hours a day and you get an ounce a week
how many people couldn't deal with 2 000
bucks extra per week
yes
the vapors of black sands are dangerous
so what you want to do is you want to
take one of these things
pipe it over to a bubble to a bubbler
okay remember i'm a big fan of safety so
just pipe it back to a bubbler
and collect the vapors in there and what
you'll find is the vapors themselves
have values in them okay
but we won't go into that
excuse me
all right
so we're here heavier elements will
always fall
now before i go to the next slide i want
to talk about something actually what is
the next slide yep okay
here's a story about how i got involved
with hydrogen in the first place now i
can see we're starting to get a little
so i'm going to tell a story real quick
here um my i was adopted by a by native
american tribe many years back and my
tribal elder came to me and said
vernon what do you think about this
hydrogen stuff is there a way to use the
hydrogen to maybe cut down on our fuel
and such and
he's as i i started playing around with
this and he describes his setup okay
literally little plastic baggies
ziploc ties holding the stainless steel
things apart
plastic baggies duct taped into a
cardboard box
little alligator electrodes clipped onto
these things and he starts describing
the amount of hydrogen he's getting out
of this thing okay he's describing
and it's splashing out of the box and
it's getting everything all wet i think
well this is very cool
he had hired three engineers
to work on
developing hydrogen for cars okay
and they were using spring water coming
out of the mountains no catalysts
using spring water and frequencies going
in there to separate the oxygen hydrogen
so they were playing around with this
and they got this red deposit on the
bottom of those little ziploc baggies
they got this red stuff starting to fall
out and it would short out their
electrodes
their plates
so they'd take it all out pour it into a
bucket refill it with spring water and
start all over again okay aft and this
bucket would fill up and and it could
dense and they fill up and it would get
redder and redder and such finally one
day they said well what is that
what is that red stuff in there
so they sent it to a lab up in la up in
salt lake
and you know what
in that bucket
they had
about four thousand dollars worth
of gold particulates
so the two and two of the engineers said
oh hell
there's no money in hydrogen there's no
future in that we want the gold
so they went and bought a houseboat on
the great salt lake
got a couple of solar panels
created a hydrogen device that that
dropped that had a space underneath
they just take the water out of the salt
lake pour it into their devices and just
let it go they get
about
two thousand dollars a month off of this
whole deal
but two thousand dollars a month
to generate a fuel that they could use
to cook and to heat and to create
electricity
and their byproduct is gold
wait a minute
paradigm shift light bulb
so
this was staring me in the face for the
last five years and
i guess it's a testament to you know the
fact that i'm i'm driven
by the universe to discover
you know new and better ways to do
everything that i didn't even think
about that okay i've known that for five
or six years i literally didn't even
think about what to do with that until
this last year when uh when some very
interesting things happen
i said i wanna i wanna i wanna explore
this so
that aside i started exploring the idea
of
using brown's gas for health and healing
and once again you can't use sodium
hydroxide because you can't have that
stuff going into your lungs so i wanted
a device that allowed me to take
literally the gas coming right out of
this thing and allow me to breathe that
without having to run it through any
bubblers or anything else i wanted it to
go directly into me when you take mono
atomic oxygen and hydrogen in the
stoichiometric ratio to make water
you put that into your body amazing
things happen
it rehydrates your tissues from the
inside out
re-energizes your tissues as a matter of
fact there's a guy here there was uh
that was talking about that i can't
remember his name um it actually
re-energizes them with a proper
electrical uh potential because the
hydrogen goes on the outside the oxygen
goes in and there's an exchange and you
get negative and positive
very energizing you re-energize your
cells which are in fact little hydrogen
fusion power plants we won't go into
that
so brown's gas pure bronze gas going
into your body is incredibly incredibly
healing and they they're they're cutting
out uh
they're they're healing chronic
migraines with this stuff because it
hydrates the tissues from the inside out
migraines are the meninges shrinking
because they're too dried out and so
they're rehydrating and they
they come back to normal
healing sprains healing all sorts of
things using the bronze gas browns gets
excuse me when ewell brown was doing uh
was doing his research he could send
people down twice as deep under water
using browns gas rather than oxygen they
could go twice as deep and come up three
times as fast no bends no nitrogen
poisoning nothing like that because
the uh the very oxygen that was going
into their bodies that was oxygenating
them was turning right back into water
and rehydrating them so there was
nothing to expand nothing to poison them
as they're coming up from the from the
ocean
so i started experimenting with that and
i discovered something very strange when
i changed the parameters
i started dropping out elements and i
was using our gold and sil or gold and
platinum and stuff like that
and i started i started dropping out
lots of elements so what what i found
was
[Music]
that these guys that were using
frequencies
here's i'm going to get
sorry this is so exciting to me i'm
almost jumping to the end and i'm trying
not to okay
um
these guys were using frequencies and
they were they were dropping out
elements okay and i talked about this
last year using a septic system
that and it's there's there's it's real
technology there's a patent back in the
70s
mitch can actually tell you about it too
they would they would purify sep the
septic water
using frequencies and giant stainless
steel plates and by the time they got to
the end it was practically distilled and
then they pulled out the various
minerals coming out of the and they sold
those as industrial compounds okay
so
the whole thing was self-sustaining
because the hydrogen and methane gas
coming off of the process was recycled
back to uh diesel generators to power
the process and it was powered by human
waste you have a power plant using no
chemicals that processes human waste and
creates viable products if that's not a
self-sufficient community technology i
don't know what is
so
yes
[Music]
you are the one telling me about it
he's the one to talk to you guys
[Music]
uh we need to we need to keep moving
because we're we're running how long
have i been talking
okay
so
this is cool because they sign these
these hydrogen guys had inadvertently
hit on a way
of
of dropping out elements out of the
water every day
14 million dollars worth of gold flows
out of colorado in the colorado rivers
one day
[Music]
in one cubic kilometer of sea water
there is 14 or something there is 24 now
24 million dollars worth of gold in one
cubic kilometer seawater
in the oil wells in southern california
they have to pump the sea water that
comes up with the they have to pump the
underground
water brine that comes up with the oil
they have to pump it back underground
27 million dollars a month
goes through there of gold not even
counting platinum
so that's something to think about as we
start looking at purifying water finding
enough drinking water not only do we
have to feed the nine billion people
we also have to find drinking water for
them
so something to think about all of these
are byproducts that help us sustain the
process
now here we come to the really
interesting
amazing part and this is why this device
is actually the coolest thing i've ever
built
because this device works off of the sun
it has no
i don't have to run it off of
electricity or anything like that i just
feed it the sun or wind power or
whatever
um
[Music]
how do i say this even without sounding
insane
there were a couple of researchers in
texas
uh 10 years back doing joe cell research
and
they decided not to put
regular water or spring water in their
joe cell what they did was they put in
clark's concentrated mineral toddy
anybody familiar with that
wow
i'm old
it's a bioavailable source of minerals
it's it's uh removed it's leached out of
uh
humic source with folic acid and it's
really really good for your body it's
bioavailable liquid minerals
they poured that into the joe cell
but they took a spectroscopic analysis
of all of the minerals in it before and
they knew exactly how much they'd poured
in there okay
they put electricity across it
separated the oxygen and hydrogen out of
there and recombined it in a bronze gas
torch and recollected the water okay
so water here separated and recombined
here okay
after a little while this thing started
fuzzing up because you can't run a
hydrogen torch you can't run a hydrogen
generator on minerals
but it starts fuzzing up and it was just
bubbling over and after a little while
it shorted out because the mineral
content was so high in the bottom of it
well that got me thinking
why
the water still looks the same
but it's concentrated at the bottom and
the rest of the water still looks the
same it
it's supposed to be dropping out right
so what they did is they took out took
that out they strained off all the extra
stuff they knew exactly how much
minerals they were putting back in they
put that back in there they put the
water back in there and started over
now wait a minute
they've got a device
they just separated it out and now
they've got more than what they started
with
so then they do it again separate the
oxygen hydrogen recombine it
drop out minerals out of the bottom
until it shorts out it fuzzes out
boils over scrapes off the minerals
filters it out puts the water back in
starts all over again they just
multiplied what they had now they got
twice as much
they did this again
now they got three times as much they
did this again they got four times as
much they did this 13 times
they multiplied their minerals 13 times
how is that possible
they didn't use up little micrometers we
went in there we measured the
micrometers
measured the the plate size
there was no plate degradation
there's nothing what we're seeing here
yes
they ended up they did spectroscopic
analysis it was exactly as if they had
they had
the exact same minerals that they had
that they started with with the clark's
minerals
they had multiplied the amount of
minerals 13 times in that process they
spectroscopically analyzed it
they ended up with 13 times more than
they started with yes
nope they used the same water all over
again they use the same water back and
forth it was a closed system and more
was coming out why is that how is that
possible yes
yeah yeah if you go to organa minerals
or they're they're they're all the same
type of minerals they're just a mineral
toddy in in liquid form
what we have done is we're now seeing
that
hydrogen and oxygen and energy is the
key to
multiplying minerals okay
i've been doing this for a long time in
my in in my alchemical studies you take
a stream of hydrogen and a stream of
oxygen
take a crystalline matrix of whatever
you want to multiply and feed etheric
energy through it the etheric energy is
patterned by the crystalline matrix goes
through the hydrogen and oxygen and you
have a spark there so the hydrogen
oxygen
becomes the material that you're working
with
boom drops out and you mult you you you
create new elements if you've ever tried
any of our electric water if you've ever
tried any of our stuff literally
it you you can do it friend of mine is
now turning our elect our uh our gold
concentrate that we have out there he
runs a process and he's selling high
purity glo gold chloride
made from water and energy what we're
looking at here now is a completely
different paradigm the paradigm that
says we can take energy and create
matter
that is the most important thing that i
have ever learned is that
water and ox or something hydrogen and
oxygen can be
can go through a template and create new
matter using just energy i challenge
each and every one of you to do this i
have done it i put
a gold concentrate a golden platinum
concentrate into this thing
we analyzed this with my friend's
detector i put a golden platinum
concentrate into this thing ran it for
three days
16 volts
one and a half amps
and what i did was i multiplied the the
golden plat the colonial golden platinum
about 10 times in that system okay
this is
the this is the this is a new age this
is like star trek replicators this is
the this is the fuel that's going to
power that
literally multiplying minerals using
hydrogen and oxygen energy
real quick one second here's a number i
said i was going to throw out some more
numbers
what's the energy density of a vacuum
i can't remember the numbers but here's
the deal in one
cubic
centimeter of the vacuum is enough
energy to power the united states for a
solid year
okay
that's in the vacuum that's not counting
protons if you guys get nausea and
higher means work and you start looking
at the real energy available
it's it's astronomical
and if you can find a way to take that
energy and imprint it and create
new matter
then you know
everything becomes possible and we have
we have the ability if we were just
looking
at the idea of dropping out minerals out
of the water that's that's plenty that's
plenty amazing you need you need
frequencies to do it we can now mine the
ocean
we don't have to put any we don't have
to dig into the ground we can mine the
ocean and drop the stuff out of the
water but if we look at this
i i couldn't be i can be crazy i don't
have any pro i don't have any connection
to being right or wrong but i know that
this is the reality we can multiply
minerals this we can multiply elements
this way and create new matter with
energy
and it's the future
of
civilization on this planet i have
always thought
since i started the hydrogen work i've
always thought that
hydrogen was an interim technology that
it would get us
from internal combustion engines to
running on
magnets running on the ether running on
on the vacuum
but but this summer as i started seeing
how much i was multiplying minerals
seeing how i mean i wasn't even just
multiplying elements
i was multiplying
uh chemical compounds that don't exist
in nature
because when i started running certain
alchemical fluids that take
take years to make
through this thing
i started making these elements or
making this fluid in a day
i couldn't believe it it took it takes
me a year
to process certain things and go through
the whole process and make this fluid
some of you have seen the gold stuff and
that that that's part of it some of you
have actually seen our our gold fluid
that we that we use to power our um our
water machine
but i was recreating it in a day
that stuff doesn't exist in nature it's
not a single element i was creating a
complex molecule that doesn't even exist
in nature in a single day